Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar can master
all four elements
and bring balance to the world.
The Equalists are on the attack.
The Lieutenant and his Chi-blockers
invaded Air Temple Island
and forced Tenzin and his family to flee.
In the daring escape,
Lin Beifong sacrificed herself
and saved the Airbenders.
But she was captured,
and Amon took her bending away.
Now, Team Avatar is in hiding,
as they await help from
General Iroh and the United Forces.
It is a glorious day,
my Equalist brothers and sisters.
Amon has torn down
the tyrannical bending government.
He has declared bending illegal.
And he has the Avatar on the run.
Our great leader
has a vision for the future.
One day soon,
bending will no longer exist,
and we will live in a world
where everyone is finally equal.
The United Forces are on their way
right now to try and stop that dream.
But we will prevail!
Can you believe Hiroshi?
"The Avatar's on the run."
I'm not running from anyone.
Let's go back up there
and knock some heads.
- They'll never know what hit 'em.
- Relax.
General Iroh's coming
with an entire fleet of battleships.
Then Amon
will be the one who's running.
I hate this "being patient" stuff.
You two were gone awhile.
We were doing reconnaissance.
Whatever.
Welcome back.
Hope you worked up an appetite,
'cause dinner is served.
Thanks so much for letting us hide out
with you the past few days.
Honored to oblige.
My associates and I heartily oppose
Amon's so-called Equalist policies.
We got benders and non-benders
livin' together down here.
But do you see us fightin'? No, siree.
We figured out
how to harmoniously coexist.
You are a wise and noble hobo.
This is the best tasting street gruel
I've ever had. Seriously.
I culled it from the finest dumpsters
the city has to offer.
Can't sleep either?
No. I have this awful pit in my stomach.
Me, too.
It's so crazy. A few months ago,
I was in the South Pole,
practicing for my firebending test,
and now I'm in the middle of
an all-out war.
I know.
We didn't even know each other then.
And now,
I can't imagine my life without you in it.
You're the most loyal, brave
and selfless person I've ever known.
I think you're pretty incredible, too,
but you already knew that.
I should probably try to get some sleep.
Me, too. Good night.
Good night.
You will now be cleansed
of your impurity.
Next.
Coast is clear.
Once the United Forces arrive, we need
to be ready to help in any way we can.
They're here.
Amon had to know we were coming.
So why aren't we
meeting any resistance?
Wait a second.
Where are the Equalist airships?
I don't see any mecha-tanks, either.
Something's not right.
It's a trick.
Water and Earthbenders,
detonate those mines.
What is that sound?
What now?
Where does Hiroshi find the time
to keep inventing new, evil machines?
Incoming!
It's all right. I've got you.
Avatar Korra?
You saved my life. Thank you.
I was prepared to deal with
Sato's mecha-tanks,
- but not these new, high-speed aircraft.
- I know.
Every time we think we have
an advantage, Amon outsmarts us.
No matter what our plan is,
he always has a better one.
Amon is winning so far,
but we're not out of the fight yet.
I like this man's confidence.
So, how are we not out of the fight?
A second wave of reinforcements
is on the way, but I need to warn them.
Do you still have a way
to get a message out?
I know just the man for the job.
And who is the recipient
of this top secret message?
Commander Bumi,
second division of the United Forces.
- Tenzin's brother?
- Yes.
Bit of a wild man, but the bravest
commander you'll ever meet.
Ready, sir.
Fleet ambushed and destroyed
by Equalist aircraft.
Retreat to Red Sand Island
until my signal.
Do not approach city
until you receive the all-clear.
Now comes the hard part.
We need to ground those aircraft.
Otherwise, Bumi's fleet
will never be able to retake the city.
They flew in from this direction.
The airfield must be
somewhere over this mountain range.
Everyone get ready. We leave at dawn.
It's time to take down my father.
Wait.
I'm sorry,
but I'm not going with you tomorrow.
- What?
- Why not?
I'm sick and tired of hiding from Amon.
It's time I face him.
That's not a good plan.
We need to stick together.
I'm not waiting for him to hunt me down.
My gut's telling me
it's time to end this on my terms.
Korra, this is not a mission
you should be handling alone.
She won't be. I'm going with you.
- You don't have to do that.
- Yes. I do.
My grandfather would respect
the Avatar's instinct.
So will I.
Love you, little bro.
Love you back, big bro.
Korra, Amon is a nasty dude. Be careful.
I will. Good luck.
If you're going into the mountains,
you should bring Naga.
Take good care of Bolin for me.
Asami.
I'm sorry
things got so messed up between us.
But whatever happens today, I want you
to know how much I care about you.
I care about you, too.
Good fortune and success to you,
valiant heroes.
There's Amon.
We need to get into the temple.
Then, when he returns...
We ambush him.
What are you two doing here?
We were just transferred.
Well, you're getting transferred again.
Amon wants extra security
at the arena today.
- The arena? For what?
- The rally.
You should have been
briefed about this.
We'll be there, sir.
I know another way in.
Let's hide in the attic.
We're not alone up here.
Tarrlok?
I don't suppose
you're here to rescue me.
We had no idea you were here.
Are there other prisoners on the island?
No. I'm the only one.
And what makes you so special?
I'm Amon's brother.
Amon is from the Northern Water Tribe.
He is a Waterbender
and a Bloodbender, just like I was.
What?
Did you know this all along?
No. Not until after he captured me.
How did your brother
end up becoming Amon?
It all began with my father, Yakone.
With the help of his former gang,
he escaped prison and underwent
surgery to change his appearance.
He assumed a new identity and settled
down in the Northern Water Tribe.
That's where he met my mother,
a warm, caring woman.
Before long,
they started a family together.
Amon was the firstborn,
under the name Noatak.
I was born three years later.
Noatak was a good-natured kid,
always looking out for me.
Those were the good years,
before my brother and I discovered
we were Waterbenders.
At first,
we were excited by our new abilities,
but our training
brought out a different side of my father.
Tarrlok, you better shape up,
or you'll be out here in the cold all night,
until you get it right.
- I'm trying, but...
- Try harder.
Your brother was never this sloppy.
Dad, he'll get it. He just needs time.
Don't talk back to me, son. Ever.
Even back then,
my brother wanted everyone
to be treated fairly and equally.
When I was seven, my father
took me and Noatak on a hunting trip,
far away from our home.
He told us his true identity was Yakone,
Republic City's
most notorious crime boss,
and that he was once
a Bloodbender of rare skill.
What's bloodbending?
The most powerful and feared form
of bending in the world.
It was declared illegal,
thanks to that coward, Katara.
Our family has the strongest line
of Bloodbenders in history.
You boys have this power inside of you.
And I will teach you to master it.
What happened to your bending, Dad?
The Avatar stole it from me.
That's why I brought you out here,
to learn your destiny.
You two will become
Bloodbenders of the highest order.
When the time is right,
you will claim Republic City,
and you will destroy the Avatar.
You must avenge me.
That is your purpose in life.
The good days were behind us.
Every full moon, our father took us on
another supposed hunting trip,
where he secretly
trained us in bloodbending.
We kept the truth from our mother.
Stop. You're hurting it.
Toughen up, Tarrlok.
You'll need a thicker skin for this.
Very good, son. Very good.
A few years later, my father
taught us to bloodbend anytime,
without the need of the full moon.
We practiced constantly,
and I hated every minute of it.
I had no stomach
for manipulating helpless animals.
My brother, however,
seemed to revel in his newfound power.
He was a prodigy, mastering my father's
psychic bloodbending technique
by the time he was 14.
That's the way it's done.
That's what you need to strive for.
Even though Noatak was my father's
favorite, it wasn't any easier for him.
He carried the burden of
all Yakone's expectations and demands.
Something changed in Noatak
over the years.
The loving brother I once knew
became cold and detached.
Our father pushed us to extremes,
and one day,
he made us bloodbend each other.
Noatak. Go.
Excellent.
Tarrlok. Your turn.
No.
I won't do it.
Bloodbend your brother, Tarrlok.
That felt awful.
I don't want to do that to anyone.
I never want to bloodbend again.
You're a disgrace, a weakling.
I'll teach you a lesson,
you insubordinate...
Stay away from him.
How dare you bloodbend me!
What are you going to do about it?
You're the weak one.
You always say bloodbending
is the most powerful thing in the world,
but it isn't. The Avatar is.
He took your bending away.
What could be more powerful than that?
I made you what you are.
You're mine.
We're your sons,
not your tools of revenge.
Let's go.
We can run away from him. Forever.
Run away? But what about Mom?
We can't just leave her.
He was right about you.
You are a weakling.
Noatak! Don't leave, please!
Noatak!
My father and I searched for days,
but we never found a sign of Noatak.
We thought he perished in that storm.
My mother was never the same
after the loss of my brother.
My father stopped training me.
With Noatak gone,
his hopes for revenge withered,
and he passed away a few years later.
That's one of the saddest stories
I've ever heard.
Avatar Korra,
I am truly sorry for all that I did to you.
I thought I was better than my father,
but his ghost still shaped me.
I became a soldier of revenge,
just like he wanted me to be.
And so did my brother.
The revolution may be built on a lie,
but I think Amon truly believes bending
is the source of all evil in the world.
How did you figure out
Amon is your brother?
When he took my bending,
the sensation was somehow familiar.
I later recognized it as
my brother's bloodbending grip.
So he somehow uses bloodbending
to take people's bending?
I don't know how he does it,
but then again, I've never encountered
a bender as strong as Noatak.
- How in the world do we beat him?
- We can't.
Any attack we throw at him,
he'll redirect with his mind.
That's how he's been able
to challenge any bender.
So much for our ambush.
If we stay here, we're toast.
- But there's another way to beat him.
- How?
This whole time,
Amon has been one step ahead of us.
But finally we have the advantage.
We know the truth about him.
If we expose him as a bender
in front of all his supporters...
At the rally.
We could take away his true power.
And undermine this whole revolution.
Thank you for your help.
- We can't just leave him here.
- Go.
Amon can't know anyone spoke with me.
Defeat him. Put an end to this sad story.