Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar can master
all four elements
and bring balance to the world.
A chance encounter turns Korra
from Pro-bending spectator
to Pro-bending star!
With her new teammates,
Mako and Bolin,
the Fire Ferrets earn a place
in the Championship Tournament!
But meanwhile, an anti-bending
revolution brews in Republic City.
Who are the Equalists?
And what nefarious plan does
the mysterious man behind the mask
have in store for our hero?
What's the big idea with making me
train this early in the morning?
The morning is evil.
We're the rookies,
so we get the worst time slot in the gym.
And you're the rookiest of us all.
We gotta get you up to speed
if we want to survive in the tournament.
Deal with it.
You deal with it.
There are my little, hard workin'
street urchins!
It's an honor to finally meet you, Avatar.
And you are?
Butakha.
I run this whole Pro-bending shebang.
Here's your winnings
from the last match.
Not so fast!
First, you owe me
for the Avatar's new gear...
Gym and equipment rentals
for last month...
Rent on your apartment...
And a personal loan for groceries.
What? I'm a growing boy!
And one more small item of business,
the Fire Ferrets need to ante up
30,000 yuans
for the championship pot.
30,000 yuans!
Sorry, kids.
You got till the end of the week
to come up with the dough,
or else you're out of the tournament.
You wouldn't happen to have
a secret Avatar bank account
overflowing with gold, would you?
I got nothing.
I've never really needed money.
I've always had people
taking care of me.
Then I wouldn't say you have nothing.
Sorry. I didn't mean...
No, it's all right. It's just...
Ever since we lost our parents,
we've been on our own.
I'm so sorry. I didn't know.
So anyway, how are we gonna
come up with the money?
I got it! I got it!
I've been training Pabu
to do circus tricks.
Now, people would pay good money
to see that!
Come on, Bolin, we need serious ideas.
I was serious.
Don't worry about it.
I'll figure something out.
I always do.
Come one, come all!
See Pabu the Fantastic Fire Ferret
as he crosses the Ladder of Peril,
upside down!
Big finish, buddy! Stick the landing!
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen!
You are too kind. Seriously, too kind.
You can come back here
and put money right in this...
Okay, that's fine, that's fine.
One yuan down, 29,999 to go.
Hey, Bolin. Is that you?
Hey there, Shady Shin!
Heard you're a big time
Pro-bending player now. Not bad!
Thanks.
So listen, I got an offer for ya.
Lightning Bolt Zolt is looking
to hire some extra muscle.
I don't know, Shin.
Mako told me to stay away
from the Triple Threats.
Your brother ain't the boss of you.
It's just a little security work,
nothin' crooked.
You game?
Bo, I'm back.
Picked up your favorite dumplings.
Hey, I found some work
down at the power plant.
Made some decent money.
Bolin? You here, bro?
I bet the little love bird
is making a house call.
Good! Light on your feet!
He's cute.
Korra, is that the handsome
Firebender boy that drives you crazy?
Does he drive you crazy in a bad way,
or does he drive you crazy
like you like him?
Hey, Mako.
- You seen Bolin?
- Nice to see you, too.
And, no,
I haven't seen him since practice.
- Think something's wrong?
- I don't know.
Bolin has a knack
for getting into stupid situations.
See you later.
Wait, I could help you look for him.
Nah, I got it.
Hey, cool guy, let me help you.
We can take Naga.
- Who's Naga?
- My best friend.
And a great tracker.
Your best friend is a polar bear-dog.
Somehow that makes perfect sense.
I'll take that as a compliment, city boy.
Well, this is his usual hangout.
You guys seen my brother
around here today?
Perhaps. My memory's a little foggy.
Maybe you can help clear it up.
You're good, Skoochy. A real pro.
Yeah, I seen him.
- When?
- About noon.
What was he doing?
He was performing
some kind of monkey-rat circus.
And then...
And then what? Why'd he leave?
Shady Shin showed up
and flashed some serious cash.
Bo took off with him in his hot rod.
The Triple Threats, the Red Monsoons,
the Agni Kais,
all the Triads are muscling up
for something real big.
Now that's all you're getting out of me!
What's he talking about?
Sounds like there's a turf war brewing,
and Bolin's about to get caught
right in the middle of it.
So where are we headed?
The Triple Threat Triad's headquarters.
Hopefully Bolin is there
and nothing's gone down yet.
Triple Threat Triad?
I beat up some of those yahoos
when I got into town.
Why would Bolin get tangled up with...
Whoa, Naga!
That's Pabu!
No, Naga. Pabu's a friend, not a snack.
We gotta hurry.
Something's not right.
There are usually thugs posted
out front. We better be cautious.
Bolin? You in here?
Bolin!
Naga! Come!
I can't bend...
I can't bend!
Calm down. It'll wear off.
Those guys were Chi-blockers.
- They're Amon's henchmen.
- Amon?
That anti-bending guy with the mask?
Yeah, he's the leader of the Equalists.
What do they want
with the Triple Threats?
Whatever it is, can't be good.
I can't believe
Bolin got himself into this mess!
Mako, we are going to save
your brother.
I promise you that.
We've been out all night.
No sign of him.
We've gotta keep looking. But where?
I have an idea!
The first day I got into town,
I ran into an Equalist protestor
over there.
And you think they'll know
where Bolin is?
It's our only lead right now.
So, why is Bolin running around with
the Triple Threat Triad, anyway?
Well, we used to do some work
for them back in the day.
What? Are you some kind of criminal?
No, you don't know
what you're talking about!
I just ran numbers for them and stuff.
We were orphans, out on the street.
I did what I had to do to survive
and protect my little brother.
I'm sorry.
It must have been really hard.
Can I ask...
What happened to your parents?
They were mugged by a Firebender.
He cut them down right in front of me.
I was eight.
Mako...
Bolin's the only family I have left.
If anything happened to him...
Equality now! Equality now!
We want equality now!
Non-benders of Republic City...
That's the guy.
Amon calls you to action!
Take back your city! It's time for...
It's you again!
You cannot silence me, Avatar!
Shut your yapper and listen up.
My friend got kidnapped
by some Chi-blockers.
Where'd they take him?
I have no idea what you're talking about!
I think you do.
"Witness the Revelation. Tonight. 9:00."
What's this Revelation?
Nothing that concerns
the likes of you two!
You better believe it concerns us.
Spill it.
No one knows what the Revelation is,
and I have no idea
what happened to your friend.
But if he's a bender,
then my bet is
he's getting what's coming to him.
Where's it happening?
Hey! What's going on over there?
The Avatar's oppressing us! Help!
Let's scram.
Why didn't the Equalists
put a location on these?
Probably because they don't want
just anyone waltzing into
their big Revelation, whatever that is.
I bet the information is hidden
on here somehow.
Look at the backs.
There's four different images.
So, it's a puzzle?
Yeah... Of a map!
Bingo! That must be
where it's going down.
This is the place.
- What are you doing?
- We'll attract less attention this way.
This is a private event.
No one gets in without an invitation.
Invitation...
You mean this?
The Revelation is upon us,
my brother and sister.
I knew a lot of people hated benders,
but I've never seen so many
in one place.
Keep your eyes out for Bolin.
Please welcome your hero,
your savior,
Amon!
My quest for equality
began many years ago.
When I was a boy,
my family and I lived on a small farm.
We weren't rich.
And none of us were benders.
This made us very easy targets
for the Firebender
who extorted my father.
One day, my father confronted this man,
but when he did,
that Firebender took my family
from me...
Then, he took my face.
I've been forced to hide behind a mask
ever since.
As you know,
the Avatar has recently arrived
in Republic City.
And if she were here,
she would tell you that bending
brings balance to the world.
But she is wrong.
The only thing bending has brought
to the world is suffering.
It has been the cause of every war
in every era.
But that is about to change.
I know you have been wondering,
what is the Revelation?
You are about to get your answer.
Since the beginning of time,
the Spirits have acted as guardians
of our world.
And they have spoken to me.
They say the Avatar has failed humanity.
That is why the Spirits have chosen me
to usher in a new era of balance.
They have granted me a power
that will make equality a reality,
the power to take
a person's bending away...
Permanently.
That's impossible. There's no way...
This guy's insane.
Now, for a demonstration.
Please welcome Lightning Bolt Zolt,
leader of the Triple Threat Triad
and one of the most notorious criminals
in Republic City.
"Boo" yourself!
- There's Bolin!
- Wait.
We can't fight them all.
We need to be smart about this.
Then come up with a game plan,
team captain.
Zolt has amassed a fortune
by extorting and abusing non-benders,
but his reign of terror
is about to come to an end!
Now, in the interest of fairness,
I will give Zolt the chance
to fight to keep his bending.
You're gonna regret doing that, pal.
What did you do to me?
Your firebending is gone. Forever.
The era of bending is over.
A new era of equality has begun!
Any ideas yet?
I think so. See those machines?
They're powered by water and steam.
If you create some cover,
I can grab Bolin without anyone seeing.
- Then, we duck out of here.
- Works for me.
Mako, good luck.
You, too.
It's not enough.
Hey, you!
Is there a problem, my brother?
What are you doing back here?
Looking for the bathroom?
Come on...
Thanks. This should be enough.
Hello, Amon, sir.
I think
there's been a big misunderstanding...
Bolin, you all right?
Yes! Mako! I love you!
You benders need to understand,
there's no place in the world
for you anymore.
I wouldn't count us out just yet.
Naga!
I want to be on your back.
The Avatar. That's her!
Let her go.
She's the perfect messenger
to tell the city of my power.
Thank goodness!
I was just about to send out
a search party. Are you all right?
Korra, what happened?
- Did you find your friend?
- Yes, but...
I was at an Equalist rally. I saw Amon.
What?
He can take people's bending away.
- For good.
- That's...
That's impossible.
Only the Avatar has ever possessed
that ability.
But I saw him do it.
I believe you.
I don't know how Amon has achieved
this power,
but this means the revolution
is more dangerous than ever.
No bender is safe.