Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar can master
all four elements
and bring balance to the world.
Love is in the air!
Since Avatar Korra
has arrived in Republic City,
she's only had eyes
for one fellow, Mako.
The feeling seemed mutual
until a fateful accident intervened.
Now, Mako's affections have fallen
right into the arms
of the beautiful Asami.
Will love prove to be Korra's
most formidable foe yet?
It's been great having you at so many
back-to-back practices, Korra.
Feels good to be back,
although Tarrlok isn't too happy
about my leave of absence.
Hey, you joined the Fire Ferrets
before you joined his task force.
Okay, come on, team huddle time!
It's our first match
of the tournament tonight.
I know the three of us haven't been
a team for very long, but even so,
the Fire Ferrets have never been
this good.
- Are we ready?
- We're ready!
Not quite. You'll need these!
- Hey, Asami.
- Good morning, sweetie.
- These new uniforms look great!
- You look great, champ!
Well, teammates,
I'll see you before the match tonight,
Asami and I have a lunch date.
Okay, we'll check you guys later,
you know,
we'll see you when we see you.
So, Korra...
There they go, here we are,
all alone in the gym.
Just you and me.
Two alone people,
together.
Alone.
I gotta head back to the Air Temple
to train with Tenzin. See you!
Work with me here, Pabu!
You want to look spick and span
in your new uniform, don't you?
So what do you think of Korra, in a
girlfriend sort of way?
She's great!
But I think it makes more sense
for me to go for Asami.
I was talking about a girlfriend for me!
Leave some ladies for the rest of us!
I know, that's what I thought you meant.
- Well?
- I don't know, Bo.
It doesn't seem like a good idea
for you to date Korra.
You just said she was great
two seconds ago.
Yeah, Korra is a great athlete
and Avatar and stuff, but...
I don't know if she is really
"girlfriend material."
- She's more like a pal.
- Bro, you're nuts!
Korra and I are perfect for each other!
She's strong, I'm strong.
She's fun, I'm fun.
She's beautiful, I'm gorgeous!
Okay, I don't care what you think,
I'm gonna ask Korra out.
Look, it just isn't smart
to date a teammate,
especially during the tournament.
Keep your head out of the clouds
and your priorities straight.
- Okay?
- Yeah, yeah, I know!
You know what I'm talking about, Pabu.
Talking about real love...
So how's it going with the tall,
dreamy Firebender boy?
You've been spending
a lot of time together lately.
Yeah, tell us all
about the magical romance.
What? Listen to you two,
I'm not interested in Mako
or any romantic stuff.
Besides, he's all into that prissy,
beautiful, elegant, rich girl.
But let's just pretend for a second
I am interested in him,
what would I do?
I just read a historical saga,
where the heroine fell in love
with the enemy general's son,
who's supposed to marry the princess.
- You should do what she did.
- Tell me!
She rode a dragon into battle
and burned down the entire country,
then she jumped into a volcano.
It was so romantic.
No, no, no!
The best way to win a boy's heart
is to brew a love potion
of rainbows and sunsets
that makes true lovers sprout wings
and fly into a magical castle in the sky,
where they get married
and eat clouds with spoons,
and use stars as ice cubes
in their moonlight punch.
For ever and ever and ever!
The volcano is starting
to make more sense to me now.
Hey, Pema.
How long were you standing there?
Long enough.
But trust me,
I know what you're going through.
Years ago, I was in the exact
same situation with Tenzin.
Daddy was in love with someone else
before you?
- That's right.
- So what did you do?
Well, for the longest time, I did nothing.
I was so shy and scared of rejection...
But watching my soul mate
spend his life with the wrong woman
became too painful.
So I hung my chin out there
and I confessed my love to Tenzin.
And the rest is history.
Folks, after a year of waiting,
the Pro-bending championship
tournament is finally here.
Tonight is the first set of matches
in our single elimination
16 team bracket.
And I gotta tell you,
these are the most
tenacious and talented
bending trios this arena has ever seen.
Introducing our first team,
the Future Industries Fire Ferrets!
And their opponents,
the Red Sands Rabbiroos.
What an explosive opening volley!
Both teams quickly recover
and unleash a barrage of bending.
I am astonished
with the level of improvement
displayed here by the Fire Ferrets.
No wonder the Avatar
has been absent from the papers lately.
She's obviously had her nose
to the grindstone in the gym.
The Ferrets advance
into Rabbiroo territory,
and they're holding nothing back.
Nice sprawl there by Mako,
Bolin strikes, Ula dodges
and all three Rabbiroos are down!
The Fire Ferrets easily take round one.
Round two!
The Rabbiroos are looking for payback,
and they go straight after Bolin.
Korra comes to his defense,
and she water-whacks
Umi back into zone two!
The Ferrets are on fire tonight,
and they win round two.
Round three!
With the Rabbiroos down two rounds,
they'll need a knockout to win,
and with the way
the Fire Ferrets are playing,
I don't see that happening.
These Ferrets are working together
like a well-oiled bending machine.
Bolin bashes Adi back into zone two,
and the Ferrets
get the green light to advance.
The Rabbiroos are just fighting
to stay on their feet at this point.
Down goes Adi, and Ula and Umi!
All three rounds go to
the Future Industries Fire Ferrets,
who win their opening match
of the tournament!
- Yes!
- That's what I'm talking about!
- Thank you, thank you very much!
- Wow, we were really connecting
- out there in that ring!
- Yeah!
You know, I feel like the two of us
have been connecting really well
- out of the ring, too.
- Sure.
So, I was thinking we should
spend some time together.
We've been spending
lots of time together.
I mean, outside of the gym.
And not while searching
for kidnapped family members
or fighting Chi-blockers.
I don't know.
- Asami and I...
- Look, I really like you,
and I think we were meant
for each other.
Korra, I'm really sorry, but...
I just don't feel the same way about you.
Forget I ever said anything.
Congratulations, guys!
You were so amazing out there.
So, Korra, I was thinking...
You and me, we could go get
some dinner together...
Sort of a date situation.
That's really sweet, but I don't think so.
- I don't feel very date-worthy.
- Are you kidding me?
You're the smartest, funniest,
toughest, buffest, talentedest,
incrediblest girl in the world!
You really feel that way about me?
I felt that way
since the moment I saw you.
Trust me, I know we're gonna have
so much fun together.
You know what? I could use some fun.
- Okay, sure.
- Yes!
Who's the luckiest guy in the world?
Right here, Bolin!
- So how'd you like it?
- It's delicious!
And totally authentic.
I didn't realize how much I missed
Water Tribe grub.
That's great,
'cause this is my favorite joint.
See? You love Water Tribe food,
I love Water Tribe food,
just another reason
we are so great together.
They are good noodles!
Hey, who's that creepy guy over there
that keeps glaring at us?
That's Tahno and the Wolf-bats.
Reigning champs, three years running.
Don't make eye contact.
Here he comes.
Now don't mess with this guy,
he's a nasty dude.
Well, well, well,
if it isn't the Fire Ferrets.
Pro-bending's saddest excuse
for a team.
Tell me, how did a couple of amateurs
like you
luck your way into the tournament?
Especially you, Avatar.
You know, if you'd like to learn
how a real pro bends,
I could give you some private lessons.
You wanna go toe-to-toe with me,
pretty boy?
Go for it. I'll give you the first shot.
Korra, don't.
He's just trying to bait you. If you
hit him, we're out of the tournament.
I've never seen someone
razz Tahno like that.
You are one of a kind, Korra.
- What kind of game are you playing?
- Pro-bending?
- We've got a quarterfinal match.
- No, I mean with Bolin.
You've got him all in a tizzy and I know
you're only using him to get back at me.
I am not, we're just having fun together.
- What do you care, anyway?
- I'm looking out for my little brother.
- I don't wanna see his heart get broken.
- Wait a second.
You're not worried about him.
You're jealous!
- You do have feelings for me.
- What? "Jealous"?
Don't be ridiculous.
Admit it, you like me.
No. I'm with Asami!
Yeah, but when you're with her,
you're thinking about me, aren't you?
- Get over yourself!
- I'm just being honest!
- You're crazy!
- You're a liar!
Hey, Mako...
Eight teams have been eliminated
and eight advance
into the quarterfinals,
which get under way tonight.
The rookies are about to take on the
former and longest reigning champs,
the Boar-Q-pines.
Youth clashes against experience
in a battle for the ages,
or rather, of the ages.
Korra dodges and
slams right into her teammate!
Down goes Mako, and Bolin and Korra!
Round one goes to the Boar-Q-pines!
You were supposed to defend
while I attacked!
I had an opening, so I took it!
What is up with you two?
All right, whatever,
just pull it together, guys.
The Ferrets looking to mount
some offense here in round two.
Bolin lets fly a flurry of attacks.
He's a one man bending battalion.
The Ferrets having a tough time
finding their rhythm tonight,
but thanks to Bolin,
they narrowly notch round two.
Not sure what's eating them,
but this is not the same team
who took out the Rabbiroos.
Round three is a tie!
We go to a tie-breaker
to decide the match.
The Fire Ferrets win the coin toss!
- Which element do you choose?
- I got this.
I know you usually handle these,
but frankly, your head's not in the game.
I'm gonna take this one.
We choose earth.
Looks like the Earthbenders will collide
in the tie-breaker face-off.
Bolin goes in for the grapple.
Chang reverses.
Bolin strikes from midair, knocking
Chang to the edge of the circle.
Another strike from Bolin,
and Chang's in the drink!
The Future Industries Fire Ferrets
win their quarterfinal match!
That was a close one, folks.
Youth trumps experience tonight.
We need to talk.
Look, sometimes you can be
so infuriating. I...
Save your breath.
You've already made it clear
how you feel about me.
No, I haven't.
What I'm trying to say is,
as much as you drive me crazy,
I also think you're pretty amazing.
- So, you do like me?
- Yes! But...
I like Asami, too.
I don't know, things are complicated.
I've been feeling really confused...
Bolin, this isn't what you think.
- Great! Look what you did!
- You're blaming me?
- You kissed me!
- You kissed me back!
Well played, Korra.
Morning, Narook. My brother here?
Thanks.
Come on, wake up.
Taking you home, bro.
Don't call me that.
You're not my brother!
You're a brother betrayer!
The only one I can trust anymore
is Pabu.
Pabu loves me.
You're a mess, and we've got
the biggest match of our lives tonight.
- Let's go.
- No!
I'm not going anywhere with you!
You traitor!
Guess I'll have to do this the hard way.
Why?
I told you dating
a teammate was a bad idea.
You're a bad idea!
Put me down!
You can't find two teams
more evenly matched
in age, size and strength
than the Fire Ferrets
and the Buzzard Wasps.
Believe me, I've looked!
This should be a pulse-pounding
semifinal, folks!
The Buzzard Wasps open with
a flawlessly executed combo!
All three Ferrets take an early visit
to zone two!
And Mako's knocked
all the way back into zone three!
The Fire Ferrets have been struggling
to stay alive since the opening bell.
All three players
are totally out of sync tonight.
That has got to sting!
And Bolin loses his noodles.
Literally! Which reminds me,
this match is brought to you
by our sponsor,
Flamey-O Instant Noodles.
Noodliest noodles
in the United Republic!
The Buzzard Wasps fly deeper
into Ferret territory.
And Mako plunges into the pool!
Can the Fire Ferrets hold on?
The Wasps have the Ferrets
backed up to the edge now.
And the Ferrets
are bailed out by the bell!
They had better pull themselves
together, folks, for round two,
otherwise they can kiss
the finals good-bye!
Hey! Watch it!
The Wasps take advantage
of Mako's unforced error,
and Bolin's in the pool!
And a blatant hold by the Avatar!
Unnecessary roughness!
Move back one zone!
I'll unnecessarily rough you up!
And the Avatar is slapped
with the yellow fan!
The Ferrets are their own worst enemy
right now.
It's just sad to watch.
With the Buzzard Wasps leading
two rounds to zilch,
the Ferrets' only hope of winning
is with a knockout.
Well, I guess there's always next year.
Come on, we still have a chance,
even if it is a slim one.
The way we're playing, we don't even
deserve to be in the finals.
Look, if we don't pull together
and work as a team,
- we'll never forgive ourselves.
- Let's just get this over with.
The sooner, the better.
Bolin's knocked into zone two,
followed quickly by his brother.
And Bolin takes a zinger
to the shoulder.
Looks like it's a clean hit.
Bolin!
Mako's in the drink
and out of the match.
And Bolin keeps playing
with one good arm!
I got to hand it to him, this kid's got grit.
But how long can he keep it up?
Apparently, not very long.
The Ferrets' dream
of making it to the finals
now rests in the Avatar's hands.
But with three on one,
I don't like her odds.
Are you okay? How's your shoulder?
It's messed up pretty bad.
But I think I'll be all right.
Are we gonna be all right?
Of course we are. We're brothers.
We'll get through this mess.
- I'm sorry.
- Me, too.
- Girls.
- Seriously.
What an unbelievable effort here
by Korra.
She's dodging every element
the Wasps throw at her.
The Avatar finally gains some ground,
but with only 10 seconds remaining,
it might be too little, too late.
It's the big kabosh! What a knockout!
- Yes!
- We did it!
Yes!
It didn't seem possible, folks,
but the Fire Ferrets
are headed to the finals!
- Shoulder, shoulder!
- Sorry!
That was pretty much
the coolest thing I've ever seen.
Thanks for not giving up on us.
We never would have
made it this far without you.
I owe you. Big time.
You're welcome.
So...
I know things are confusing right now.
- But I hope we can still be friends.
- Definitely.
You boys smell something in here?
Wait, I know what that is.
Yeah, that's the scent of losers.
I hope we see you in the finals.
Then we'll see who the losers really are.
Yeah.
I'm peeing in my pants over here.
And now, the defending champs,
the White Falls Wolf-bats!
Great job!
What a comeback, Korra!
- I've never seen a hat trick like that.
- Thanks.
But if it hadn't been
for you and your father,
we wouldn't have had
the chance to play.
So, thank you.
If everyone's done
with the little thank you party,
I need some
medical attention over here!
Let me help!
Haven't you hurt me enough, woman?
Relax, I'm a healer.
I learned from Katara, the best there is.
No, no, no, no...
That's the stuff.
Bolin, I'm sorry I hurt your feelings.
I didn't mean to let things
get so out of hand.
I'll be all right.
- But we had fun together, didn't we?
- I had a great time, honestly!
You are one of a kind, Bolin.
Please, go on. I enjoy praise.
Your winners!
The Wolf-bats!
What? How is it over already?
With a brutal round one knockout,
the defending champs
secure their spot in the finals.
I hope the Ferrets know a good doctor,
because they're gonna need one!