Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar can master
all four elements
and bring balance to the world.
The Avatar has been abducted!
After Tarrlok arrested her friends,
Korra confronted the councilman
in his chambers.
But the heated argument quickly turned
into an all-out bending battle.
Desperate to save himself,
Tarrlok revealed his ability to bloodbend
and took Korra far from Republic City.
Will the Avatar's friends find her
before it's too late?
What are you doing?
Tarrlok!
You can't keep me in here forever!
Who is this? It's 6:00 in the morning,
this better be important.
Councilman Tenzin here.
What?
What happened?
What was Korra doing at City Hall?
As I told Chief Saikhan,
Korra came to my office late last night.
She was upset
that I arrested her friends.
She asked me to release them,
and that's when the Equalists attacked.
I tried to protect Korra,
but we were outnumbered.
Then, I was electrocuted.
When I came to, the police had arrived,
but Korra was gone.
I'm so sorry.
Chief Saikhan,
mobilize the entire police force.
We have to find the Avatar.
We interrupt
your regularly scheduled broadcast
to bring you this special report.
Late last night,
Equalists attacked City Hall,
subduing Councilman Tarrlok
and capturing Avatar Korra.
Details are still coming in, but...
Hope you got enough beauty rest.
Come on, I'm busting you out.
Thanks, I owe you.
Are you done yet?
Cover your ears.
I can't go with you listening!
Asami!
A little privacy, please!
Are you all right?
I'm fine. It's so good to see you.
Hate to break up your lovers' reunion,
but Korra's in trouble.
Amon captured her.
No. No, she can't be gone.
Come on, we have an Avatar to rescue.
Your fly was down.
Thanks for catching that.
Somebody! Help! Please!
Please...
I urge you to meditate on these visions.
I believe Aang's spirit
is trying to tell you something.
What are you doing here, Aang?
I told you, I have this under control.
Under normal circumstances,
I wouldn't get involved.
But if what those victims said is true,
we're not dealing
with a normal criminal.
Fine. Follow me, Twinkle Toes.
Toph, I'm 40 years old,
you think you could stop
with the nicknames?
Afraid not.
It's over. You're under arrest, Yakone.
What is Republic City coming to?
Used to be,
a man could enjoy his lunch in peace.
What's the big idea?
We have dozens of witnesses, Yakone.
We know what you are.
Take him away.
I've beaten every trumped-up charge
you yahoos have brought against me,
and I'll beat this one, too!
I finally connected with you, Aang.
But what are you trying to tell me?
A way out of this box would be nice.
I have to go.
Call me back
the minute you hear anything.
Lin, what are you...
You should be in the hospital!
And you three, you should be in prison!
I figured you could use our help
finding Korra.
Do you have any leads?
I've been on the phone all morning,
but, nothing yet.
We need Naga. She can track Korra.
I'm afraid her polar bear-dog
is missing as well.
Then where do we start?
My guess is
the Equalists are hiding underground
in the maze of tunnels beneath the city.
Underground,
just like my father's secret factory.
Figures.
Yeah, yeah, that makes sense.
When those Chi-blockers had me
in their truck,
it sounded like we drove into a tunnel.
I know where to start looking. Come on!
Wherever Amon is keeping Korra,
I bet that's where my officers are, too.
Let's bring them all home, Lin.
The truck with Bolin took off
down this alley.
Which way?
This way kind of smells familiar.
There's a tunnel nearby.
There!
Motorcycle tracks.
Korra has to be in there...
Somewhere.
Let's try this way.
And what if Korra's not down there?
Then we pick another tunnel
until we find her.
Hey, is Mako all right?
He seems really worried about Korra.
Yeah, we all are.
I know, but he's your brother.
Do you think he likes Korra
as more than just a friend?
What? No. That's just gossip,
where'd you hear that?
Crazy talk is coming out
of your mouth right now.
What do you know, Bolin?
Come on, spill it.
Nothing! I mean...
There was this one time
during the tournament
when Mako and Korra kissed, but...
They kissed?
Believe me, I was upset, too,
but I'm over it.
I don't think it meant anything.
I doubt that.
Hide!
That tram goes to the training camp.
Everything was delivered
to the prison, sir.
That's where
they must be keeping Korra.
We need to get down that tunnel.
- It's empty.
- Yeah, I can see that.
You two keep an eye on them.
My officers are inside.
What about Korra?
I don't see her yet.
Avatar Korra,
where are you keeping her?
Chief Beifong?
I'm too late.
That monster already took
your bending, didn't he?
I'm so sorry.
Come on, let's get you out of here.
I'll ask you one more time.
Where is she?
We don't have the Avatar.
And the Equalists didn't attack City Hall.
- Tarrlok's lying.
- What?
I scanned the entire prison.
Korra's not here.
Why would Tarrlok make up a story
about getting attacked?
Because he has Korra. He fooled us all.
Let's go, people!
Try to Chi-block that, fools!
We got more company!
Hang on!
Yakone has ruled Republic City's
criminal empire for years.
Yet he has always managed
to stay out of the law's reach,
until now.
You will hear testimony
from dozens of his victims.
And they will tell you
Yakone has maintained his grip
on the underworld
by using an ability
that has been illegal for decades,
bloodbending.
The prosecution's entire case
is built upon the make-believe notion
that my client is able to bloodbend
at will,
at any time, on any day.
I remind the Council
that bloodbending
is an incredibly rare skill,
and it can only be performed
during a full moon.
Yet the witnesses will claim
that my client used bloodbending
at every other time,
except during a full moon.
It would be a mockery of justice
to convict a man of a crime
that is impossible to commit.
Councilman Sokka will now deliver
the verdict.
In my years, I have encountered people
born with rare
and unique bending abilities.
I once bested a man
with my trusty boomerang
who was able to firebend with his mind.
Why, even metalbending
was considered impossible
for all of history,
until our esteemed Chief of Police,
Toph Beifong,
single-handedly developed the skill.
The overwhelming amount
of testimony and evidence
has convinced this Council
that Yakone is one
of these unique benders.
And he exploited his ability
to commit these heinous crimes.
We find Yakone guilty of all charges
and sentence him to life in prison.
Thank you all for meeting us
on such short notice.
- Chief.
- Lin.
Have you news of Avatar Korra?
We do. You kidnapped her, Tarrlok.
I am shocked you would accuse me
of such an evil act.
I already explained,
Equalists attacked us and took her!
But there were no Chi-blockers here
last night.
You planted the evidence, didn't you?
That is a ridiculous accusation!
It's true! He took her!
I was here when Avatar Korra
arrived last night,
but Councilman Tarrlok
ordered me to leave.
I was on my way out
when I saw Tarrlok bring her down
to the garage...
Say goodbye to Republic City,
Avatar Korra.
You'll never see it again.
That is nonsense!
Everyone knows you're nothing
but a squeaky-voiced liar!
Why did you wait until now to fess up?
I was terrified to tell because...
Because Tarrlok is a Bloodbender!
He bloodbent Avatar Korra!
Don't make this worse for yourself.
Tell us where you have Korra.
Wake up.
Man, I had this awful dream
that Korra was taken
by this evil Bloodbender.
So weird.
Bolin, that really happened.
He knocked us out.
Are you serious? Where is he?
Is he here right now?
Tarrlok is long gone.
I'll alert the whole force.
We've only been out for a little while.
Maybe we can still pick up
Tarrlok's trail.
It could lead us to Korra. Let's go.
Yakone, you won't get away with this!
Republic City is mine, Avatar.
I'll be back one day to claim it.
This time, I'm gonna put you to sleep
for good!
I'm taking away your bending, for good.
It's over.
Aang, this whole time,
you were trying to warn me
about Tarrlok.
My life is a disaster now, thanks to you!
So your little bloodbending secret's out?
And I know how you bloodbent me
without a full moon.
You're Yakone's son!
I was his son.
But in order to win Republic City,
I had to become someone else.
My father failed
because he tried to rule the city
from its rotten underbelly.
My plan was perfect.
I was to be the city's savior.
But you... You ruined everything!
Tarrlok, the jig is up
and you have nowhere to go.
No. No, I'll escape and start a new life.
And you're coming as my hostage.
You'll never get away with this!
Amon!
It is time for you to be equalized.
You fool. You've never faced
bending like mine!
What... What are you?
I am the solution.
I'll take care of him.
You four retrieve the Avatar.
Do not underestimate her.
Electrocute the box to knock her out
before you open it.
My pleasure.
It's payback time.
Open the box.
Tie her up.
I thought I told you
not to underestimate her.
Naga, you came looking for me.
Good girl.
That sounds like Naga!
Down there!
Korra!
Thank goodness!
Where's Tarrlok?
How did you get away?
Give her some space.
I was so worried. Are you all right?
I'm fine.
I'm glad you're here.
You're safe now.